[{"id": "601371c0138175489539638d", "question": "Which musician wrote the theme song for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Paul Anka -- The song earned him massive royalties. According to Anka, he received $200 every time the song was played.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2d", "question": "What was Mark Twain's real name?", "answer": "Samuel Clemens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba7", "question": "Cheyenne is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe526621bf59ab7d2e380f7", "question": "What is the coldest permanently inhabited town on Earth?", "answer": "Oymyakon, Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394fe", "question": "In the SNL Digital Short \"Lazy Sunday\", what movie were the characters going to see?", "answer": "The Chronicles of Narnia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce8", "question": "What singer-songwriter played bass in the New Wave band \"'Til Tuesday\"?", "answer": "Aimee Mann", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2a8", "question": "What year did Humphrey Bogart die?", "answer": "1957", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a3126c0f9723ab15cb49", "question": "What was the first department store?", "answer": "Harding, Howell and Company Grand Fashionable Magazine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c9", "question": "What body organ produces insulin?", "answer": "The pancreas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c376d815febcc896f9270", "question": "What year did Dashiell Hammett publish the novel \"The Maltese Falcon\"?", "answer": "1929", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b1c", "question": "In what 1992 movie does Jennifer Jason Leigh play a dangerous \"roommate from Hell\"?", "answer": "Single White Female", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93af6ce05a3942286e91", "question": "Andy Dufresne was particularly skilled and knowledgeable in what in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Finance and Taxation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b838", "question": "What 1960s invention was originally called the \"Pleasure Pit\"?", "answer": "Waterbed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba497874c93a3298b2146", "question": "What is believed to have eventually killed Oliver Cromwell?", "answer": "Malaria and urinary/kidney infection", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c148", "question": "How many double stitches are there on a regulation baseball ball?", "answer": "108", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e2c", "question": "What musical was based on Thornton Wilder's play \"The Matchmaker\"?", "answer": "Hello, Dolly!", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a9", "question": "What are the four main levels of India's caste system?", "answer": "Brahman, Kshatriyas, Vaisyas, Sudras", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc5", "question": "Who is the wife in Shakespeare's only interracial married couple?", "answer": "Desdemona", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa56cec73aa70ea0b70b2d", "question": "Which two towns were destroyed and buried when Mount Vesuvius erupted in 79 A.D.?", "answer": "Pompeii and Herculaneum were both destroyed by the eruption in 79 A.D.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133920c", "question": "In which TV show is the local fast-food restaurant called \"The Chum Bucket\"?", "answer": "SpongeBob SquarePants", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb75", "question": "What is the name of Ronald McDonald's big purple friend who loves McDonald's milkshakes?", "answer": "Grimace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e5f116ed274615ecf514539", "question": "What is the name of Olive Oyl\u2019s sister-in-law?", "answer": "Cylinda Oyl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd9757e83c707845b217a", "question": "How old was Sheldon Cooper when he earned his PhD?", "answer": "He went on to earn himself a PhD at the young age of 16.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7fd", "question": "In what layer of the Earth's atmosphere is Antarctica's famed \"ozone hole\"?", "answer": "Stratosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd822e5d0de9af39e9d46ac", "question": "How many vice presidents did FDR have during his time in office?", "answer": "3", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb6d565ff7d326b622a9a", "question": "Who was known as \"The Sultan of Swat\"?", "answer": "Babe Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f30", "question": "What literary locale is called \"Manor Farm\" at the start of the novel?", "answer": "Animal Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b94a", "question": "Who was the jeweller to the Russian Court famous Easter eggs?", "answer": "Peter Carl Faberge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba88", "question": "Whose death is described in the last chapter of the Torah?", "answer": "Moses", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cf7abb53d1af658864f4", "question": "In the film \"Home Alone 2\", what city was the McCallister family planning on vacationing in?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea36a2ff048f679a45ab10", "question": "What animal is sometimes used by museums to clean skeletons for display?", "answer": "Beetles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c789", "question": "The Earth's ozone layer absorbs what type of radiation from the Sun?", "answer": "Ultraviolet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d7", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his role in the film 'The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c9", "question": "How many feet make a mile?", "answer": "5,280", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c89d11011619dd6d415482", "question": "While pretending to be an inner city calculus teacher, what was Eric Cartman\u2019s catch phrase in South Park?", "answer": "How do I reach these keeeds?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c703", "question": "What famous 19th-century American writer was issued a patent for adjustable elastic suspenders?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c730", "question": "What vitamin group, important for vision and bone growth, includes retinol?", "answer": "Vitamin A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe733b0eec85e375820b224", "question": "What was Australia's original purpose as a colony?", "answer": "To be a British prison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590720463745b36be73039f0", "question": "In the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", what did my true love send to me on the eighth day?", "answer": "8 Maids a-Milking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66a", "question": "Anna's, Calliope, and Ruby-throated are species of what bird?", "answer": "Hummingbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b25401dd7bf43be5e79c", "question": "\"And Bob\u2019s your uncle\" is typically used in which way?", "answer": "Conclude a talking point", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b48b749076251badbeaa5", "question": "Who was the oldest person to travel in space?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He was 77-years-old when he returned to space on the Space Shuttle Discovery's STS-95 mission.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b515", "question": "What is the crucial card in the game of Hearts?", "answer": "The queen of spades", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b540", "question": "What language was left unpunctuated until the modern age?", "answer": "Japanese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b1", "question": "In what century did Leonardo Da Vinci paint the \"Mona Lisa\"?", "answer": "16th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a948", "question": "What city is the eastern terminus of the Trans-Siberian Railway?", "answer": "Vladivostok", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca0", "question": "What 1980s TV shows featured sisters Missy and Tracey Gold, respectively?", "answer": "\"Benson\" and \"Growing Pains\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc81", "question": "In 1964, who founded Blue Ribbon Sports, which later went on to become Nike?", "answer": "Phil Knight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad05", "question": "Where were the 1996 Summer Olympics held?", "answer": "Atlanta, Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8841ec223966ae8f881d", "question": "Tamla Records is the former name of which well-established record label?", "answer": "Motown Records", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c50a", "question": "How many baby teeth does a child usually have?", "answer": "20", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ab", "question": "What Guns N' Roses star decided his real name, William Bailey, wasn't cool enough?", "answer": "Axl Rose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba45", "question": "What is the official state dessert of Massachusetts?", "answer": "Boston Cream Pie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0e", "question": "The Battle of Bunker Hill occurred during what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ae", "question": "Whose movie character's full name is Charles Lee Ray?", "answer": "Chucky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede5766ce05a3942286ded", "question": "What was the first cooking show on television, hosted by James Beard in 1946, called?", "answer": "\"I Love to Eat\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63b", "question": "Which blood type is a universal? donor", "answer": "O negative", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c53", "question": "\"Martin Chuzzlewit\" and \"The Olde Curiosity Shoppe\" are novels by what author?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d5d", "question": "What classic movie, in which Charlton Heston is miscast as a Mexican cop, is sometimes called the last \"film noir\"?", "answer": "Touch of Evil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03a", "question": "Who received the third most popular votes in the 1992 US Presidential election?", "answer": "Ross Perot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc36cec223966ae8f887e", "question": "Which Disney pricess has the least amount of screen time?", "answer": "Aurora from \"Sleeping Beauty\" gets only 18 lines and 18 minutes of screen time.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d10", "question": "What nationality was author Jules Verne?", "answer": "French", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b857", "question": "What number is represented in Morse code by 5 dots?", "answer": "5", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd2", "question": "In biblical etiology, which animal became extinct because it was thrown off the ark and drowned?", "answer": "The unicorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba81", "question": "On what part of your body would you wear mukluks?", "answer": "The feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c6510775fa611bce67d1", "question": "What short-lived product did Pepsi introduce in 1992?", "answer": "Crystal Pepsi -- Marketed during the 1993 Superbowl with an ad featuring Van Halen, it did well at first. It later fizzled.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca9", "question": "Al Pacino's satanic character in \"The Devil's Advocate\" is named for what author?", "answer": "John Milton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea77bfff048f679a45abce", "question": "Meningitis is characterized by what major symptoms?", "answer": "Stiff neck, sudden high fever and a severe headache", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339187", "question": "According to \"Futurama\", how much does 1 lb of Dark Matter weigh?", "answer": "Over 10,000 lbs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c4", "question": "What is the Japanese alcoholic drink sake made from?", "answer": "Rice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60077f15bd51d85e222ab63b", "question": "In biology, a relationship between individuals of two species in which one species obtains food or other benefits from the other without either harming or benefiting the latter is called what?", "answer": "Commensalism", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e1", "question": "What does FIFA stand for?", "answer": "F\u00e9d\u00e9ration Internationale de Football Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4dd8306d333868d34d703", "question": "Eric the Red was a Viking from what period of time?", "answer": "900s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c72b", "question": "What organ in the human body produces insulin?", "answer": "Pancreas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd668e7a5bfecdd737e0874", "question": "Why is \"pound\" abbreviated as \"lb\"?", "answer": "\"Libra\" is Latin for pound or weight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a0", "question": "What movie starred Johnny Depp as Willy Wonka?", "answer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c72d", "question": "What is odorless and tasteless in its purified form, and used in cooking to set aspics?", "answer": "Gelatin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974f", "question": "What 2 coaches on The Voice first appeared in season 4 and returned for season 6?", "answer": "Shakira & Usher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa52b2c73aa70ea0b70b1d", "question": "What Caribbean island is known as \"Little England\"?", "answer": "Barbados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b135", "question": "The Gadsden Purchase involved the lower portions of what are now which two US states?", "answer": "Arizona and New Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea369aff048f679a45ab0f", "question": "What is the \"Big Dipper\" known as in England?", "answer": "The Plough", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb7", "question": "In The Green Lantern comic book series, what is the color used to represent will power?", "answer": "Green", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fedddea6ce05a3942286da8", "question": "Which actress claims she cried when she was shown her wardrobe for the role of the monarch in the 2006 film \"The Queen\"?", "answer": "Helen Mirren", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398df", "question": "What year did Marty McFly go back into in the movie \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9d", "question": "What national news magazine published its first issue in February 1933, as a competitor of \"Time\"?", "answer": "Newsweek", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010ca4c0775fa611bce67f6", "question": "What is another name for rubbing alcohol?", "answer": "Isopropyl alcohol -- It is a germicide that is effective against bacteria, viruses, and fungi.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7d062877e98cb97778a60", "question": "Tarawa is located in what group of islands?", "answer": "The Gilbert Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388bc", "question": "What game does the Queen of Hearts order Alice to play?", "answer": "Croquet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbb", "question": "What novelist of westerns went by his middle name, since his first was Pearl?", "answer": "Zane Grey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa05", "question": "Which mountain range lies in the north of Spain, west of The Pyrenees?", "answer": "The Cantabrian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17a", "question": "What object is said to bring bad luck if it is broken?", "answer": "Mirror", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ecaeb8c790ded87bb38fd8f", "question": "Which major motion film marks Bob Saget's directorial debut?", "answer": "Dirty Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a153", "question": "Who is Placebo's lead singer?", "answer": "Brian Molko", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000ed109a72b906b34e3ce8", "question": "What hormone allows the cells in your body to absorb sugar from your blood?", "answer": "Insulin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7d00c877e98cb97778a5a", "question": "What U.S. state is closest to Africa?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d24", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Breaking Away\"?", "answer": "Bicycle racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9d8", "question": "Where does the famous \"running of the bulls\" take place?", "answer": "Pamplona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c069", "question": "On May 1, 1991, Nolan Ryan threw his seventh and final no-hitter against which Major League team?", "answer": "The Toronto Blue Jays", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b1bae662d71a53650fd3", "question": "What short novel did John Steinbeck originally call \"Something that Happened\"?", "answer": "\"Of Mice and Men\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b358a0b5db0d66a186cb550", "question": "Which ocean does the African country, Burundi, has access to?", "answer": "None", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3a", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Billy the Kid\"?", "answer": "Billy Joel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c26", "question": "Who began hosting the \"Texaco Star Theater\" in 1948?", "answer": "Milton Berle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b3235f5bf195a31e15d73b4", "question": "Who played the electric piano on the Beatles track \"Get Back\"?", "answer": "Billy Preston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42a", "question": "In what country would you see \"whirling dervishes\"?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339332", "question": "In what year did the TV show \"The Hills\" premier on TV?", "answer": "2007", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a88290aac110e416708f", "question": "Which American colonial beverage was produced by freeze-distilling cider throughout the cold winter months?", "answer": "Applejack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c152", "question": "What is a group of locusts called?", "answer": "Plague", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5921fbfea4edfd43a087adbe", "question": "What is the symbol of the Zodiac sign Leo?", "answer": "The Lion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea6", "question": "What hobby uses the Yoshizawa-Randlett diagramming system?", "answer": "Origami", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399d4", "question": "What 1994 cult film featured a day in the lives of characters Dante and Randal?", "answer": "Clerks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65592ae7e414034b5aeb4", "question": "What material was the first artificial Christmas tree made from?", "answer": "Goose feathers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beeb", "question": "What Is Joseph Cyril Bamfords claim to fame?", "answer": "Founded JCB", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e24", "question": "What kind of dinosaur is the Flintstones' Dino?", "answer": "A snorkasaurus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc1", "question": "What band's Greatest Hits album set a US record by going 29 times platinum?", "answer": "Eagles'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a0ed20565ad31a57c79d", "question": "Who created the centigrade scale?", "answer": "Anders Celsius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59b", "question": "What is the granular substance that bees collect called?", "answer": "Pollen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909cc7fbb53d1af658864e1", "question": "Who created Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "Robert Lewis May", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cdd98e347d002c297e4f2", "question": "Who wrote the collection of short stories on which Fiddler on the Roof was based?", "answer": "Sholem Aleichem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d3", "question": "The Jupiter II spacecraft was featured in what TV series?", "answer": "Lost in Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac4", "question": "What \"C\" word is the name for a two-hulled boat?", "answer": "Catamaran", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7ca04877e98cb97778a00", "question": "What is the capital of the British Virgin Islands?", "answer": "Road Town", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fc", "question": "What year did Frederick Forsyth publish the novel \"The Deceiver\"?", "answer": "1991", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d7", "question": "What fruit is \"Citrus grandis\"?", "answer": "Pomelo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac1e", "question": "Paramaribo is the capital of which South American country?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa9596ce05a3942286ee0", "question": "What was the name of the Lone Ranger\u2019s horse?", "answer": "Silver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015ec6afe83fe1f2a824c01", "question": "What does the final day of Passover celebrate?", "answer": "The arrival of the Israelites to the Red Sea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea31c0ff048f679a45aae4", "question": "What is the most common form of stalactites?", "answer": "Speleothems", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6012186963c99d48cd169af2", "question": "Minnesota, it is illegal to tease what type of animal?", "answer": "Skunk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339427", "question": "What character was Bela Lugosi best known for playing?", "answer": "Dracula", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a10", "question": "What year was the setting for the movie \"Animal House\"?", "answer": "1962", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b0bfe662d71a53650fcb", "question": "In Harry Potter's world, what is the first name of Andromeda Tonks daughter?", "answer": "Andromeda Tonks daughter and only child is Nymphadora Tonks.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523ec4736d4be723796b53", "question": "What three provinces requested a single Dominion be formed in 1867, thus beginning to shape modern Canada?", "answer": "New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and the Province of Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97a", "question": "The French Tennis Open is played at which venue?", "answer": "Roland Garros", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0be", "question": "In the traditional song, what did the children dance around \"on a cold and frosty morning\"?", "answer": "The mulberry bush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d2", "question": "How many claws does a domestic cat have?", "answer": "18", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e6bc59fb6c85e9e634ff5c", "question": "Who sang \"All I Wanna Do\"?", "answer": "Sheryl Crow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eb2", "question": "What Broadway musical featured the song \"New York, New York\"?", "answer": "On the Town", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b347", "question": "What toy was released in 1958 creating an instant craze among children?", "answer": "The Hula Hoop", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c902fbde8045e48466e6", "question": "Which farm animal sleeps standing up?", "answer": "Horses are the only farm animal that can sleep standing up, and it's due to the unique way their legs are structured.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b00", "question": "Which character killed Fyodor Karamazov?", "answer": "Smerdyakov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d73", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"Life Among the Lowly\"?", "answer": "Uncle Tom's Cabin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339050", "question": "Which Russian writer composed \"Peter and the Wolf\"?", "answer": "Sergei Prokofiev", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde5210c6c6b019850c9a94", "question": "Who did Luke write the Book of Acts to?", "answer": "Theophilus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f1", "question": "In 1917, Finland declared its independence from what country?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c34c", "question": "What element makes up the majority of the air in Earth's atmosphere?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b358a485db0d66a186cb552", "question": "Which countries does Bangladesh share a land border with?", "answer": "India and Myanmar (Burma)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910e", "question": "What current-day country was writer, neurologist and psychiatrist Viktor Frankl born in?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6bb", "question": "What river is located along the southern border of Texas?", "answer": "Rio Grande River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e3", "question": "Mary Lou Retton won five medals in what sport at the 1984 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Gymnastics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078af70eee65b76b9f2662", "question": "Kleenex was invented to serve what purpose during World War I?", "answer": "Kleenex was originally invented for use as a gas mask filter. Kimberly-Clark remarketed Kleenex in 1924 as a makeup remover.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a49220565ad31a57c7bf", "question": "Which President kept a 1,000+ lb. block of cheese in the White House?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b608", "question": "In what decade did the Vatican withdraw their requirement that Catholics refrain from eating meat on Fridays?", "answer": "The 1960s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b6", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Principal Charming\", where does Skinner buy an engagement ring for Patty?", "answer": "The Family Jewels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c2", "question": "What do the letters MG stand for in the British sports car?", "answer": "Morris Garage", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3d", "question": "The 2002 film \"Confessions of a Dangerous Mind\" was based on the unauthorized autobiography of what former gameshow host?", "answer": "Chuck Barris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7ebc7b24f84e0b9f9ffe0", "question": "Which drummer led a band called \"The Jazz Messengers\"?", "answer": "Art Blakey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b869", "question": "What kind of beans are dropped into a Sambuca?", "answer": "Coffee beans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f84bfe83fe1f2a824c2b", "question": "The first Plague that befell Pharaoh of Egypt was?", "answer": "The first plague that tore through Egypt was the Nile turning into blood", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac9", "question": "In what year did the French author Charles Perrault die?", "answer": "1703", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c903", "question": "What is an emasculated stallion called?", "answer": "Gelding", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5c", "question": "Who was the Greek God of Love?", "answer": "Eros", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ae", "question": "What name is given to rain with a particularly low pH?", "answer": "Acid rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592eadcff83302ff91e46481", "question": "What is the Ali G's full name?", "answer": "Alistair Leslie Graham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c1", "question": "What country proclaimed the birth of its billionth citizen in 2000?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c52d", "question": "What bird can swim but cannot fly?", "answer": "The Penguin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594a63662ebb971c1417fb99", "question": "Who performed the 1977 song \"Let's All Chant\"?", "answer": "The Michael Zager Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d5", "question": "Philip Guichet is credited with inventing which popular cocktail?", "answer": "The Grasshopper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe12d95e39efa6330e0fecd", "question": "Which country pioneered the concept of \"Gross National Happiness\"?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69f1720565ad31a57c78a", "question": "The first woman to run for president chose whom as her running mate?", "answer": "Fredrick Douglas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb6", "question": "Who invented the spinning Jenny?", "answer": "James Hargreaves", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b025", "question": "In July 1957, Althea Gibson became the first African-American to win what sporting event?", "answer": "Wimbledon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4ed9606d333868d34d76e", "question": "In what type of language does the meaning change based on your pitch?", "answer": "Tonal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d0", "question": "Who directed the 1956 film \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Charles Walters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf6", "question": "What drink is sometimes called \"the green fairy\"?", "answer": "Absinthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5954e9c48e82ccaf3b9a67bd", "question": "What food group is a cucumber technically in?", "answer": "Fruits", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937e9a508d98002fdd6339b", "question": "Who is Donald Duck's girlfriend?", "answer": "Daisy Duck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e78906d333868d34d73f", "question": "Who was known as the \"Mad Monarch\"?", "answer": "George III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a48b90aac110e416706c", "question": "Zymology, also known as zymurgy, is the study of what?", "answer": "Fermentation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d47", "question": "What folk hero is said to live in the Sherwood Forest?", "answer": "Robin Hood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a863", "question": "The popular tourist destination, Amalfi, is located in which province in the Italian Campania region?", "answer": "Salerno", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e5", "question": "In \"Rocky 3\" what does Apollo Creed give as a gift before he fights \"Clubber\" Lang?", "answer": "Boxing trunks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8aa9201dd7bf43be5e75d", "question": "In flight systems, what does the initialism \"TCAS\" stand for?", "answer": "Traffic Collision Avoidance System", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa74", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Kentucky?", "answer": "Frankfort", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a646", "question": "What river flows through Utah's Glen Canyon?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbf", "question": "When did construction of the Berlin Wall begin?", "answer": "1961", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6aa", "question": "What cave, found in central Kentucky, is the world's longest cave system?", "answer": "Mammoth Cave", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c801", "question": "What invisible \"color\" can bees see on flower petals?", "answer": "Ultraviolet, or Bee purple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6017373744491cbd7c5a1786", "question": "What is the name of the iron-clad ship that engaged the CSS Virginia during the American Civil War?", "answer": "On March 9, 1862, the CSS Virginia engaged the USS Monitor off Hampton Roads, Virginia in a naval battle that resulted in a draw.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b866", "question": "What chess piece makes an L-shaped move?", "answer": "Knight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0fa", "question": "Which Andrew Lloyd Webber musical is set in the \"Troubles Of Belfast\"?", "answer": "The Beautiful Game", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fed2bd0ec223966ae8f8913", "question": "In the film \"Dances with Wolves,\" what happens to Dunbar's diary?", "answer": "It's used as toilet paper.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b41c", "question": "What year did Cambodia declare its independence from France?", "answer": "1953", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3d6944f0f6af5b06663a", "question": "What group were Gerry Rafferty and Billy Connolly in?", "answer": "The Humblebums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac23", "question": "What countries share land borders with Suriname?", "answer": "French Guiana, Guyana, and Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21a", "question": "What Labrador retriever supplanted Socks the cat as the Clintons' favorite pet in 1997?", "answer": "Buddy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b6", "question": "What movie stars Marlon Brando as a boxer who stands up against a corrupt union?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59d", "question": "What word denotes the energy an object has because it is in motion?", "answer": "Kinetic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff20f6e31a458464a93c434", "question": "Who wrote the 1952 novel \"Invisible Man\"?", "answer": "Ralph Ellison", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e5", "question": "What is known as a \"Magnum Opus\"?", "answer": "The greatest, most popular or most renowned achievement of a writer, artist or composer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d70", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Space Odyssey\"?", "answer": "2001", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600241c04be4723ccac2217c", "question": "Which Dutch artist painted \"Girl with a Pearl Earring\"?", "answer": "Vermeer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c57c", "question": "What volcanic rock floats in water?", "answer": "Pumice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad0", "question": "Which author set most of his book in the year 802,701?", "answer": "H.G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c919", "question": "What type of number has no factors other than 1 and itself?", "answer": "Prime", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d44", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Minority Report\"?", "answer": "Samantha Morton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b046", "question": "When did the American Revolutionary War end?", "answer": "1783", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c0", "question": "In The Simpsons, who is Cletus, the slack-jawed yokel married to?", "answer": "Brandine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c059", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Latvia?", "answer": "White wagtail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339baf", "question": "What knighted English actor played Gandalf in \"The Lord of the Rings\" film trilogy?", "answer": "Ian McKellan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5eb738325e259d786908732e", "question": "What book by George Orwell had a film adaption that was funded by the CIA?", "answer": "Animal Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c996", "question": "Heroin is the brand name of morphine once marketed by which pharmaceutical company?", "answer": "Bayer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a99cc61d1b4d384d5d69f", "question": "What tennis player earned the nickname the \"Ice Man\"?", "answer": "Bjorn Borg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7c", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Doris Mann in the novel \"Postcards from the Edge\"?", "answer": "Debbie Reynolds", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a725", "question": "Mount Whitney is the highest peak in which mountain range?", "answer": "Sierra Nevada Range", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9ae8ebfabb9c85d8a980", "question": "The \"Althing\" is the national parliament of which country?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc0d1c469bb8041d07a058", "question": "Which country did ices or sorbets originate in?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a111", "question": "What does the \"E\" stand for in Wile E. Coyote's name?", "answer": "Ethelbert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdd5e5d0499cffc60b84234", "question": "According to the Bible, who requested the head of John the Baptist on a silver platter?", "answer": "Herodias", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f2a1ff048f679a45aaba", "question": "What do you call an organ that produces gametes?", "answer": "Gonad", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e0", "question": "Which TV character has the surname \"Sagdiyev\"?", "answer": "Borat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133add6", "question": "What wonder of the ancient world was destroyed by arson the same night Alexander the Great was born?", "answer": "The Temple of Artemis at Ephesus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b2f901dd7bf43be5e7a5", "question": "What team retired Michael Jordan\u2019s jersey despite him never playing for them?", "answer": "Miami Heat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d7", "question": "Who traditionally occupied the Peacock Throne?", "answer": "The shah of Iran", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5aab2e5258d116dab4aecb3d", "question": "In Olympic competitions, what are the heights of the diving boards?", "answer": "3 and 10 meters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c28a", "question": "What element's chemical symbol is Pb?", "answer": "Lead's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c4c", "question": "What author's headstone includes the phrase \"Quoth the Raven, Nevermore\"?", "answer": "Edgar Allen Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c4", "question": "What term for a rocket's propulsive force is calculated by multiplying its exhaust velocity by the burn rate of its fuel?", "answer": "Thrust", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e2b", "question": "Who is Jamie Lee Curtis' mother?", "answer": "Janet Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bce", "question": "Which pair of German brothers collected such stories as \"Hansel & Gretel\"?", "answer": "The Brothers Grimm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1cc", "question": "Whose execution caused the famed Spanish Armada to sail against England?", "answer": "Mary, Queen of Scots'", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0aa", "question": "What kind of a head does a Criosphinx possess?", "answer": "Ram", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008adbcf842fa4c4ba9694", "question": "What is the name of the lively Spanish dance in triple time and typically performed with castanets or tambourines?", "answer": "Fandango", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133becd", "question": "How many Witches are in a coven?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc5cbec223966ae8f8883", "question": "Bruce Willis played a convict turned time traveler in what 1995 movie?", "answer": "\"12 Monkeys\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339073", "question": "What is the author of \"The Bonesetter's Daughter\", \"The Joy Luck Club\", and \"Sagwa, the Chinese Siamese Cat\"?", "answer": "Amy Tan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b918e662d71a5365102c", "question": "\"The Color Purple\" begins, \"You better not tell nobody but\" who?", "answer": "God", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339784", "question": "What saxophonist released the 1964 album \"A Love Supreme\"?", "answer": "John Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af58", "question": "The Nuremberg Trials were held during which years?", "answer": "1945 and 1946", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c534", "question": "A pluot is a hybrid of what two fruits?", "answer": "Plum and apricot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1de", "question": "In the restaurant world, what does the term \"Omakase\" translate to in English?", "answer": "I'll leave it up to you", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393dd", "question": "What is the real first name of the singer Boy George?", "answer": "George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be46", "question": "The VIC-20 and PET were personal computers manufactured by which company?", "answer": "Commodore International, Ltd.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feccc20ec223966ae8f88a1", "question": "How long did it take to render each frame (1/24th of a second) of the CGI scenes in the movie \"Avatar\"?", "answer": "47 hours", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c00d", "question": "What are the two primary ingredients that go into a Hollandaise sauce?\u00a0", "answer": "Butter\u00a0and egg yolks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2cf", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Red Baron\"?", "answer": "Manfred von Richtofen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff6679c52a821ff76ae8afe", "question": "Which historical member of British royalty made Christmas trees mainstream there?", "answer": "Prince Albert, the German husband of Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fff", "question": "Who wrote the best selling novel \"Polo\"?", "answer": "Jilly cooper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca4", "question": "What is the heating element in Hasbro's Easy-Bake Oven\"?", "answer": "A lightbulb", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339560", "question": "In the movie It's a Wonderful Life, who lost $8,000?", "answer": "Uncle Billy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cacc", "question": "Which bone is known as the Patella?", "answer": "The kneecap", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c9", "question": "Who directed the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Henry Koster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a82a", "question": "What is the largest country in Africa in terms of land size?", "answer": "Algeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa57fbc73aa70ea0b70b37", "question": "Which U.S. state features the Italian phrase \"Fatti maschii, parole femine\" as its state motto?", "answer": "Maryland  (The motto translates as \u201cManly deeds, womanly words.\u201d\u00a0 The state uses\u00a0\"Strong deeds, gentle words\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c683", "question": "Which metal, in its purest form, has the highest melting point?", "answer": "Tungsten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b0", "question": "What group of chemicals is responsible for the heat in chili peppers?", "answer": "Capsaicinoids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb7b", "question": "In the 1890's, what type of cheese did a California man named David Jacks introduce?", "answer": "Monterey Jack", "category": "general"}]